





WHO AM I?

My main programming languages and skills:

1.Python(6 years) 2.SQL(3 years) 3. ETL(4 years) 4.AWS(4 years) 5.Docker(4 years) 6.Databricks/Spark(3 years) 7.NodeJS/ReactJS/Typescript(2 years)

As a curious and detail-oriented person, I value understanding things in deep. Team work is an important trait for me and I'm always seeking for environments where there's plenty of collaboration, innovation and freedom to create and to fail.

Furthermore, in any project I work on, I focus on some key aspects. The first one is the quality of the software/data I'm delivering, they need to be top-notch. I also aim for a solid and well designed architecture, because that keep things easy to maintain and to scale. Good documentation and usability are important too, I work hard to deliver something that's smooth for users and for future developers. And, finally, observability, because it helps on spotting problems and troubleshooting.

EXPERIENCE

4/2023 - 9/2024 1 yr and 6 mos

Sr Software Eng. | Data Ingestion Platform

Nubank

On Data Ingestion team we are responsible for:

- Maintain more than 10 services in order to ingest data from a myriad of sources into Nubank's Data Lake
- Develop new data incremental ingestion platform following the Data Mesh concept of decentralisation and ownership, ingesting more than 25 bi events per day

Scala / Spark / DeltaLake / Clojure / AWS / Kafka / Kubernetes / Databricks / BigQuery

3/2022 - 3/2023

1 yr 1 mo

Data Engineer | Data Platform

I oft

Python / FastAPI / Spark / Databricks / DeltaLake / AWS / SQL / Docker StitchETL

8/2021 - 2/2022

Data Analytics Engineer

Pagar.me

Tableau / SQL / Airflow / AWS / Docker / Python / Data Modeling

1/2021 - 8/2021

part time

Automation Software Engineer

- Created automations inside the team, speeding up and ensuring quality of the main processes
- Improved the technical level of the existing systems, solved technical debt, solved architectural problems and improved system design

/ SQL / AWS / Docker / Python / DataDog / NodeJs

1 yr and 4 mos

9/2020 - 12/2021 Fullstack Software Engineer | MLOps

NextCam

- Design and build the MLOps application for Nextcam's main product, improving the performance of training of new models and tunning of old ones
- Design, create, and deploy the CI/CD for all Nextcam's applications
- Improve quality/architecture practices in the Engineering team
- Develop product strategy

FastAPI / Python / Postgres / AWS / Docker / NodeJS / Typescript / ReactJS / Heroku

8/2020 - 12/2020 Backend Teaching Facilitator | Django

Kenzie Academy

4 mos

- Course/syllabus structuring
- Composition of course materials, as well as capstone projects and exercises practices
- Students learning process monitoring
- Career mentorship as developer
- Test and develop new methodology for teaching with open source projects Python / Django REST Framework / Postgres / AWS / Docker

8/2020 - 12/2020 Backend Teaching Facilitator | Django

- Course/syllabus structuring

- Composition of course materials, as well as capstone projects and exercises practices
- Students learning process monitoring
- Career mentorship as developer
- Test and develop new methodology for teaching with open source projects Python / Django REST Framework / Postgres / AWS / Docker

6 mos

5/2020 - 8/2020 Frontend Developer and Project Manager

Humanoide.co

Kenzie Academy

- Implemented mobile app with highly customized components and UI in React Native, Styled-Component and SASS (without templates), for San Francisco startups
- Developed frontend application with highly customized UI (without templates) with SASS and BEM methodology, for San Francisco startups
- Improved and lead team agile rituals
- Proposed new tech squads structures for best development
- Lead several meetings with customers to gather product and software requirements React Native / JavaScript / HTML / SAAS / Heroku / Scrum / Agile Methodologies / Software Requirements

12/2016 - 1/2020 Co-founder

3 yrs and 2 mos

RoadieBot

RoadieBot is a music-tech startup that empowers musicians and engineers to control and release all their rig potential through gear automation.

- built the startup since the early stage using scientific entrepreneurship methodology, interviewed more than 160 stakeholders to validate business and product strategies
- designed and developed all the desktop app versions of the product, integrating it with the hardware device (electronJS, arduino, python)
- in the last 18 months of the startup, led dev team and developed all tech product: hardware + software (electronics, motors, 3D printing, software dev)

Python / JavaScript / HTML / CSS / ElectronJS / NodeJS / Agile Methodologies / Software Requirements / Arduino / Electronics

EDUCATION

2011 - 2017 Electrical Engineering, BSc.

Universidade de Brasilia

Graduation Thesis: Typography Pattern Recognition System (python, openCV, scikit-learn, dataset composition and image processing)

Prof. Dra. Mylène C.Q. Farias

2014 - 2015

Electrical and Electronic Engineering, Interuniversity Exchange Bachelor Brunel University London Graduation Thesis: Queue Simulation for H264 Video Codec (Matlab).

Prof. Dr. John Cosmas.

LANGUAGES

NON PROFIT

Portuguese(Brazil) - native **English** - proficient Italian - intermediate

I gave mentorship to 10+ professionals who wanted to switch their career to software, and the program is still open.